<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>more or less insightful</title>
    <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on more or less insightful</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020 Leesoo Ahn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ooseel.net/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title># 월간 인사이트 - 2021년 6월호</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2021/06/hashtag-montly-insight-2021-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2021/06/hashtag-montly-insight-2021-06/</guid>
      <description>General  &amp;lsquo;월간 인사이트&amp;rsquo; 시작  안도형님이 작성하신 This month I Learnd을 보고 시작했다. 포스트하는건 귀찮지만 인사이트를 얻은 글에 대해 월 단위로 정리하여 공유하기에 좋은 방법이라 생각한다. 기억속에 고이 잠든 인사이트 넘치는 글들이 너무나 많다!   평범한 일상이 소중한 이유  퇴근 후 맥주 한 잔, 저녁 노을을 보며 뛸 수 있는 여유. 30대에 들어서며 20대에 가졌던 생각이 많이 바뀌었다. 20대에는 지금의 나는 내 인생에서 두번 다시 오지 않아!라며 악착같이 열심히 경험쌓으며 살았다.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design SIOCGIFADDR on IPv6 socket</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2021/02/design-siocgifaddr-on-ipv6-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 21:26:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2021/02/design-siocgifaddr-on-ipv6-socket/</guid>
      <description>As some of you already know SIOCGIFADDR isn&amp;rsquo;t supported on IPv6 socket although SIOCSIFADDR is. For sure there is a reason linux kernel doesn&amp;rsquo;t do so but it&amp;rsquo;s worth to build up by our hands, then we get to know much more in detail. This is good for us as a studying purpose rather than use in product.
We define simple ideas with some requirements, then look at kernel patch and a demo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020년을 되돌아 보는 글</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2020/12/look-back-to-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 07:07:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2020/12/look-back-to-2020/</guid>
      <description>1년을 되돌아 보는 행동은 언제나 낯설고 긴장된다. 자기 반성을 위해 지난 1년간의 활동을 객관적으로 바라봐야 하는데 이 곳에 말은 못해도 가슴 쓰린 기억들을 끄집어 내야하니 말이다. 이 글은 나를 되돌아 보는 글이다.
9월부터 실내암벽 등반을 다시 시작했다. 지금은 2.5단계로 인해 쉬고 있지만 1월에 그만둔 뒤로 8개월만이었다. 회사-집-공부 패턴으로 몇 달을 지내니 스트레스가 풀리지 않아 불면증에 슬럼프까지 겹쳤는데 자존감 측면에서 확실히 운동하고 안 하고의 차이가 존재한다. 땀을 확 빼고 집에 갈 때 느끼는 밤 공기의 상쾌함, 이 느낌은 여전히 내가 살아 존재하는 느낌을 준다.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricky Signal Tracing in Kernel</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2020/12/tricky-signal-tracing-in-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 21:35:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2020/12/tricky-signal-tracing-in-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever experienced such horrible signals between core processes which might crash a whole system? I had done. Unknown signals are a kind of critical issue in product.
Someone says &amp;ldquo;Better safe than sorry&amp;rdquo;. I like that quote. Even though software world is totally chaotic on bugs, we should at least try some approaches being safe. Especially signals. They never log while on their way unless we trigger so that could quietly stab your back one day if you are off the guard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Pinky and Programmable Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2020/08/vim-pinky-and-programmable-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:01:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/me/2020/08/vim-pinky-and-programmable-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>I use my left pinky to jump back and forth in vim with cscope, ctags + vim comb a lot everyday. Especially ctrl + t, o, ] and so on. However, it has been hurt slightly. I thought that it might be by the use of the pinky a lot, so that looked for a solution in Google. Firstly, I could have modified my input method program a bit such that swap between Ctrl and Caps Lock, but felt frustrated all the steps code level to testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.ooseel.net/me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ooseel.net/me/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>